https://github.com/probinso

## Personal Statement

I am currently a masters student at OHSU, studying computer science with projects in image, signal, and text processing. In my several years of industry experience and prior degree, I developed strong interests in scientific computing, information retrieval, machine learning, programming languages, reproducible research, and education. I have adapted to, and adopted, a new tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. I am hoping to help you understand, and better yet solve, interesting and valuable problems.

### Persistant Experience :

C, C++ Python Linux TDD

R, dplyr ET<sub>E</sub>X Git. Ticketing Systems

# Work Experience \_

#### - Graduate Research Intern NASA Jet Propulsion Lab

June 2018 - Sept. 2018

Designed & developed Expert Modeling/Recommender System, by extending the Author-Topic-Model Prototyped matching experts against mission critical anomalies, automating expensive tasks Implemented stable/principled text normalization, tokenization, and model evaluation Open Source contributions to the gensim's natural language processing library

Technologies : Python, gensim, pyLDAvis, pandas, jupyter

## OHSU Fair Neuroimaging Lab - Research Assistant

Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Contributed to workflows and analytics tools for studying Microbiome populations Supported research on developing brains, including ABCD, and several ADHD/ASD studies Developed processing pipeline and audit tools for reported data and FMRI images

Technologies: Python, Bash, R, neo4j, ponyorm, stan, GitLab

## Contractor/Consultant

ComScore

## RGB Optics / C&W Energy USA

Nov. 2015 - Present

June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Developed low cost spectral profile analysis and custom photo image processing Authored educational material in light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Developed a cloud memoizing data pipeline for caching computationally expensive operations Provided live technology tutorials and consulting on optimization and image processing

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis

PDXCodeGuild June 2016

Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable remote-first workflow Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Technologies: Python, numpy, skimage, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++, Jira, ZenHub

#### - Research Engineer April 2014 - Dec 2015 Galois Inc.

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware

Developed processing pipelines and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Technologies: Python, SLURM, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker, Jira, Basecamp

#### EMC<sup>2</sup> Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Technologies: C, C++, Python, SQLite, Subversion, FreeBSD, OpenSSL

#### - Mentors Program Director Sept. 2009 - March 2012 Computer Science Dept.

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation

Technologies: Ada, C++, Scheme, R, mercurial

# Neato Projects

Topic modeling and applications, for non-statisticians  $BT_{F}X$ Whale vocals localization and analysis scipy, Python Workshop collaborative introduction to GitHub and slides markdown, bash, github.api Morphological Watershedding Algorithms pyspark, numpy, ndimage, Python Relevance Vector Machine Julia Information Retrieval Cluster/Rank Demo Harness flask, numpy, nltk, sklearn, Python Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor R, caret Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Sagemath Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Sagemath, Erlang Multilingual Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada Fractal Art Generator C# Image Manipulation Program C# Unix Shell  $\boldsymbol{c}$ С Liars Dice Game Server

## Education

## Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

Computer Science MSc 2016 - present

### Courses :

\* Deep Learning

\* Artificial Intelligence
Digital Signal Processing
Problem Solving with Large Clusters
Image Processing
Machine Learning

Information Retrieval
Computing Ethics
Statistical Methods
Univariate Statistical Analysis
Analysis of Sequences

## Western Washington University

Computer Science

Computer Science BS, Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

### Electives :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Functional Programming Computer Graphics
Number Theory
Elementary Real Analysis
Abstract Algebra
Linear Algebra I/II